sometimes time plays an important role
有时时间很重要
in in in strategic situations things
在战略形势下
take step one after the other and not
一步一步走，而不是
only do they do but the actors know that
他们只是这样做，但是演员们知道
they will and that influences how they
他们会并且那会影响他们
behave so the year was 1519 and amnon
举止如此，这一年是1519和阿农
Cortez Spaniard was leading a flotilla
西班牙科尔特斯（Cortez Spaniard）带领一支舰队
of eleven boats and about 600 men about
共有11艘船，约600名男子
to invade a continent later to be known
后来入侵一个大陆
as America they were vastly outnumbered
作为美国，它们的数量远远超过了
and were well aware of the the heavy art
并且非常了解繁重的艺术
they were facing and as is famously
他们面对着，众所周知
known as they landed Cortes ordered that
当他们降落时，科尔特斯下令
all the both be burnt this not
都被烧毁了这不是
controversy whether this was done in
争议是否在
complete coordination and agreement with
与之完全协调并达成协议
his men or it was sprung on them but
他的手下，或者突然冒出来，但是
either way it's clear what the logic
无论哪种方式，很清楚逻辑是什么
behind it was the quartet Cortes knew
后面是四重奏Cortes知道
that as they faced these daunting odds
当他们面对这些艰巨的可能性时
the men would be tempted to turn back
男人会很想回头
board the boat and and flee and by
登船逃离
removing eruption that increased their
消除增加他们的喷发
fighting resolve going forward and so
战斗决心前进等等
again there's not only the fact that
不仅如此，
time passes between actions but that one
时间在行动之间流逝，但是那一个
reasons about that fact and impacts how
有关该事实的原因并影响
the strategic situation unfolds we see
我们看到的战略形势正在发展
it not only when there are multiple
不仅有多个
agents involved but even in a single
代理商参与，但即使是一个
decision maker here it's not only Cortes
这里的决策者不仅是科尔特斯
and his men the two actors or the two
和他的手下两个演员或两个
sets of actors who are somehow actions
演员以某种方式行动
are intertwined but even with a single
交织在一起，即使只有一个
actor the fact that time unfolds can
演员事实证明时间可以展开
impact the situation here's another
影响情况，这是另一个
famous historical tale in this case of
在这种情况下的著名历史故事
Ulysses and the sirens
尤利西斯和警报器
Ulysses is captaining his boat and about
尤利西斯（Ulysses）正在指挥他的船，
to pass through the straits of the
穿越海峡
sirens and as is commonly known the
警报器，众所周知
sirens song are so seductive that they
警笛声很诱人
would cause any person in victory
会导致任何人胜利
Ulysses to do things there are in his
尤利西斯做他的事
own not not in his own best interests he
自己不符合自己的最大利益
would jump into the sea he would crash
会跳入海中，他会坠毁
the boat against the rocks and so what
船靠在岩石上等等
he does according to the tale he order
他按照他订购的故事来做
is always a man to first put wax in the
总是一个男人先在上面放蜡
ears so they will not be seduced by the
耳朵，所以他们不会被诱惑
song he himself who in fact wants to
自己想唱的他自己
hear the song knowing that he would not
听这首歌知道他不会
be able to withstand the seduction
能够承受诱惑
orders he's meant to time to the mast
他本来想去桅杆的命令
and should he possibly get free from the
他是否应该摆脱困境
from the tithe to restrain him with his
从什一税来约束他
swords and and and and so so it comes to
剑与和与之所以如此
pass they sailed through the Strait when
当他们驶过海峡时
they when he hears the siren song he
他们当他听到警笛声时
goes temporarily insane and tries to
暂时疯了，试图
escape from the bond that fails and all
逃离失败的纽带
is good so here again is single action
好，所以这里又是一个动作
in this case Ulysses reasoning about the
在这种情况下，尤利西斯（Ulysses）关于
future thinking about what will the
未来思考什么
situation be at taking action now to
情况正在采取行动
impact what the strategic situation will
影响战略形势
look like in the future to model such
将来像这样建模
situation we turn to games in extensive
情况我们转向广泛的游戏
form as the term is called sometimes
有时称为形式
simply known as game truth
简称为游戏真相